## **BABATUNDE OLUWASEGUN ADEKUNLE**

oluwasegunababatunde@gmail.com | +2348034372743

# **SUMMARY**

Energetic and curiosity-driven software developer with 5+ years of experience writing top-quality clean code for high-paced businesses. Eager to support eTop in modernizing its world-class products and delivering an incredible user experience. In previous roles created a backend library for enterprise scale applications used in to process payments.

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# ELKANAH IT TECHNOLOGIES – Achievement Highlight 2018 – Present

# **Full Stack Developer**

- Developed native Android applications and frameworks using Kotlin and Java.
- Defined and implemented robust app architectures and complex user interfaces.
- Applied expert knowledge of Android system frameworks to solve novel problems.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.
- Facilitated customization of systems by encouraging software engineering team to adopt emerging standards for software application development architecture and tools.
- Excelled in rapid application development and management of technological issues for assigned projects.
- Partnered with product managers, designers, and analysts to deeply understand the needs of users and build a file sharing product that serves those needs.
- Made technology recommendations by staying up-to-date on new development and platforms, keeping an eye out for the right tool for the job, and taking the lead in setting up those tools.
- Worked closely with customer support to respond quickly to user issues, permanently solve them, and reduce the turnaround time of fixes.

#### **PROJECTS & KEY ACHIEVEMENTS**

# ➤ POS (Point of Sale) Integration

- Lead developer in the integration of Point of Sales Terminal (mobile and android). Developed an injector application for the IPEK, AID, Public key, and other transaction parameters.
- Implemented the SDK from OEM into an android app.
- Building of third-party API for existing applications.
- Integrating mobile Bluetooth printer for the printing of transaction receipt
- Ensuring a secure transaction following JWT encryption technique

# ➤ Widerpay Products

- Created and managed an e-Banking wallet for payment and collection of bills,
- Developed a Widerpay transaction monitoring system to monitor transactions. It implements the ISO8085 framework, and the App collects data directly from the Nigerian central switch and the Nigeria Interbank settlement.
- Built a Widerpay Admin Application for managing all aspects of the wallet system. It comprises of the reconciliation module, KYC module, Enrolment module, VAS and POS management module, support module.
- Develop OTP Authentication Mobile App for verification in place of Hard token and mail/SMS OTP.
- Integration of bill, airtime, data, and similar services using CoralPay VAS Integration system.

## ➤ Waste Management System (Web and Mobile App)

- Collaborated with other developer team to build and managed a waste management system, which is hosted on both web and Mobile Application.
- Allowed integration with a payment portal to allow remission of bills.
- Migration of data from MySQL to MSSQL Server
- Develop different modules on both mobile app and web app for Waste Manager, Property Owner, Agent, Users, and Admin.

### > Student Web Portal (ANAN and NCA)

- Designed and developed frontend and backend for the Nigerian College of Accountancy portal.
- Built an admin web app for the uploading of result and granting of admission.
- Designed and developed frontend and backend for the Association of National Accountant of Nigeria mobile app for their payment and validation services.
- Built an admin mobile app for the Association of National Accountant of Nigeria payment and authorization verification services.

#### ➤ Revenue Collection Product

- Designed and developed mobile app for collection of taxes at benue state.
- Built an admin and uploader mobile app for the uploading of settlement excel file and granting of approval for settlement by the admin.

# > Other projects worked on at Elkanah

- Booking and Appointment Website (Australia)
  - o Designed and developed the frontend and backend systems of an hospital booking system.
- Designed API interface used to connect with the Hospital internal software for SMS notifications.
- Flutter Package for POS Integration
  - Developing new and supporting existing user-facing features
- Translating designs and wireframes into high quality code
- Baxi (Capricon's) mPOS Web Payment Gateway
  - Using pure vanilla Js to build the payment frontend
- Baxi (Capricon's) iOS mPOS Payment Gateway
  - o Optimizing components for maximum performance across a vast array of capable devices
- Implemented the SDK from OEM into an iOS app
- Develop Library and API integration of POS transaction for agents like Lagos state health centre.
- Develop Android and iOS app for Accelerex and integrate POS purchases with it.
- Development of Roemich Int'l School Mobile App for Student and Lecture.
- Development of FuelNow Mobile App for selling of Fuel using digital system at fuel stations.
- Implementation of Kendo MVVM using JS and JQ as an architecture for web development.
- Implementation of MVVM for mobile development on both Android studio, Xamarin, and XCode.

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

# Freelance Agent and IT Consultant: March 2016 – Present

# **Position: Full-Stack Software Developer**

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions on Mobile, Web, and Desktop apps like:
- Facial Student Attendance
- AXIS API (Banking system Web App, API, and Database)
- Reconciliation App (To compare two excel file and point out where they have similar or different data)
- Mobile Apps with Ads Integration for earning.

- Online Car Sales
- Restaurant Management System
- Stock management System
- Online Student Assignment Submission
- Airline Reservation System
- E-Voting
- Estate/Hotel Management System
- Image Steganography, and so on.

# MSG System, Basel, Switzerland: December 2017 - Present

# **Position: Junior Software Developer**

- Develop, maintain and manage IT software solutions with a senior developer at Switzerland remotely. Some of our project during collaboration include:
- Bible-or-metal (Quiz: To see if you can tell if the quote is from the bible or a metal song.)
- Humanoid-readable (Blog for Java beginner)
- Creation of Java Utilities like:
  - o smallset (Fast bit set operations for byte values.),
  - Enum-bit-set (EnumSet and BitSet in one!),
  - o Streamed-sql (Use Java Stream API for your Java Database Connectivity (JDBC) queries.).

# **LANGUAGES**

C#.NET / VB.NET

JAVA / KOTLIN

XML / XAML

ASP.NET CORE MVC / ASP.NET FRAMEWORK MVC

ASP.NET RAZOR MVC / ASP.NET BLAZOR MVC

Progressive Web App (PWA)

HTML / CSS / Bootstrap / JavaScript / NodeJS / Typescript

MS SQL SERVER

### **EDUCATION**

## **B.Sc, Computer Science: In-View**

National Open University of Nigeria, Ilorin, Kwara state, Nigeria. (2021 – Present)

# ND, Computer Science (2017-2019)

# 3.60, Distinction Class Honors, Lower Division

• Federal Polytechnic Offa, Offa, Kwara state, Nigeria.

| CERTIFICATIONS, TRAINING & AWARDS   |         |
|---|---------|
| Jobberman Soft Skills Training Certification  | 2021    |
| <ul> <li>MegaRich Consults &amp; Networks LTD Certification of Proficiency</li> </ul> | 2018    |
| <ul> <li>NASS Overall Best Student, Computer Science</li> </ul>                       | 2019    |
| NACCOSS Best Student in ND  | 2018/19 |
| <ul> <li>Second Runner at NACCOSS Software Exhibition Programme</li> </ul>            | 2018/19 |

# **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

Em&Em Info-Tech Solution, Offa, Kwara, Nigeria: August 2018 – 2019

# Position: Software Developer/Instructor

- Instruct young programmers on web and desktop app development using C#.NET, VB.NET and ASP.NET.
- Effectively managed approximately 50 young programmers daily.

#### **HOBBIES**

- Skateboarding, Biking, and Hiking.
- Video Gaming.
- Vacationing and exploring IT Solution.
- Training young people in programming.

# REFEREES

Available on request